<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cabezas, Mariano</author><author>Oliver, Arnau</author><author>Lladó, Xavier</author><author>Freixenet, Jordi</author><author>Bach Cuadra, Meritxell</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A review of atlas-based segmentation for magnetic resonance brain images</title><secondary-title>Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine</full-title></periodical><pages>e158-e177</pages><volume>104</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Atlas</keyword><keyword>Automated methods</keyword><keyword>Brain</keyword><keyword>Magnetic resonance imaging</keyword><keyword>Segmentation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2011</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ireland Ltd</publisher><accession-num>21871688</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cmpb.2011.07.015</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cabezas et al. - 2011 - A review of atlas-based segmentation for magnetic resonance brain images.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2011.07.015</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Normal and abnormal brains can be segmented by registering the target image with an atlas. Here, an atlas is defined as the combination of an intensity image (template) and its segmented image (the atlas labels). After registering the atlas template and the target image, the atlas labels are propagated to the target image. We define this process as atlas-based segmentation. In recent years, researchers have investigated registration algorithms to match atlases to query subjects and also strategies for atlas construction. In this paper we present a review of the automated approaches for atlas-based segmentation of magnetic resonance brain images. We aim to point out the strengths and weaknesses of atlas-based methods and suggest new research directions. We use two different criteria to present the methods. First, we refer to the algorithms according to their atlas-based strategy: label propagation, multi-atlas methods, and probabilistic techniques. Subsequently, we classify the methods according to their medical target: the brain and its internal structures, tissue segmentation in healthy subjects, tissue segmentation in fetus, neonates and elderly subjects, and segmentation of damaged brains. A quantitative comparison of the results reported in the literature is also presented. © 2011 Elsevier Ireland Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ravi, Venkata</author><author>Sai, Mohana</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Multi Atlas Fusion Methods for Medical Image Segmentation</title></titles><periodical/><volume>5747</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://EPFL_TH5747.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rohlfing, Torsten</author><author>Maurer, Calvin R.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Shape-based averaging</title><secondary-title>IEEE Transactions on Image Processing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Transactions on Image Processing</full-title></periodical><pages>153-161</pages><volume>16</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Combination of segmentations</keyword><keyword>Shape-based averaging (SBA)</keyword><keyword>Shape-based interpolation (SBI)</keyword><keyword>Signed Euclidean distance transform</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2007</year></dates><accession-num>17283774</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/TIP.2006.884936</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1.1.77.7118.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A new method for averaging multidimensional images is presented, which is based on signed Euclidean distance maps computed for each of the pixel values. We refer to the algorithm as &quot;shape-based averaging&quot; (SBA) because of its similarity to Raya and Udupa's shape-based interpolation method. The new method does not introduce pixel intensities that were not present in the input data, which makes it suitable for averaging nonnumerical data such as label maps (segmentations). Using segmented human brain magnetic resonance images, SBA is compared to label voting for the purpose of averaging image segmentations in a multiclassifier fashion. SBA, on average, performed as well as label voting in terms of recognition rates of the averaged segmentations. SBA produced more regular and contiguous structures with less fragmentation than did label voting. SBA also was more robust for small numbers of atlases and for low atlas resolutions, in particular, when combined with shape-based interpolation. We conclude that SBA improves the contiguity and accuracy of averaged image segmentations. © 2006 IEEE.</abstract></record></records></xml>
